# Rangga Perkasa Aprili Sugiyanto Software Engineer

Tulungagung, Indonesia | +6281249888836 | ranggaperkasa822@gmail.com | linkedin | https://github.com/RanggaPerkasaAS

## **SUMMARY**

Hello, I am a graduate of Telkom Malang Vocational School majoring in Software Engineering who is currently studying at Bina Nusantara University majoring in Information Systems. I master the Javascript programming language and usually use the NodeJS and Express frameworks.

I have 1 year of work experience in SIMTEK (Simbiotik Innovation Technology) in the field of Software Developer. As a software developer there, I worked on several projects, namely developing the company's website using Laravel, developing the frontend (Next JS) and backend (Nest JS) of the dashboard website admin, and most recently being the Backend Developer of the hospital Dashboard project using Express JS.

In 2021, I have internship experience at PT Artha Elektronika (EzyPay) for 3 months as a software engineer there I helped develop the web from the utter academy with the PHP programming language and the Codelgniter framework

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## PT Simbiotik Innovation Technology (SIMTEK) – Tangerang, Banten, Indonesia Software Engineer (August 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2023) Fulltime

- Develop simtek websites using the Laravel framework.
- Develop dashboard website admin using Next JS for Frontend and Nest JS for Backend.
- Develop the backend of the Hospital dashboard website for admin using Express.

## PT Artha Elektronika (EzyPay) – Malang, Indonesia

Software Engineer (JULY 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021) Internship

- Help develop 5 pages of the Utter Academy website using PHP language, and Codelgniter framework
- Re-design UI UX of the utter academy course page

#### **EDUCATION**

## **BINA NUSANTARA UNIVERSITY ONLINE LEARNING (2023 - present)**

Majoring in Information Systems

## **SMK TELKOM MALANG (2019 - 2022)**

Vocational High School of Software Engineering

## **ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE**

## Paskibra SMK TELKOM MALANG

Co - Leader (December 2020 - December 2021)

- During my tenure as Co-Leader, I was often a presenter at weekly forum activities and became a regular trainer for weekly training
- managed to create a combined training event with other extracurriculars

## HARD SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Java
- PHP
- Nest Js
- Next Js

- Node Js
- React Js
- MySQL
- Postgree
- HTML & CSS

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- High Loyalty
- Responsible
- Teamwork

- Critical Thinking
- Honest

## **PROJECT**

#### Simtek Website

Laravel (August 2022 – September 2022)

- Creating Website simtek using Laravel framewok
- In this projet I use MYSQL as a database

#### **Web Admin Laundry**

NodeJS & ReactJS (NOVEMBER 2020 – FEBRUARY 2021)

- Creating API and CRUD using NodeJS framework
- Make frontend from laundry with ReactJs framework
- In this project I use MYSQL as the database

## **PYP Project Show Case Niaga**

ReactJS (JUNE 2021)

• Creating a website showcase of group business ideas with the ReactJS framework

#### **Utter Academy Website**

**CODEIGNITER** (JULY 2021 – SEPTEMBER 2021)

- Internship project to develop 5 page the utter academy website using the PHP programming language and the Codelgniter framework
- Re-design UI UX of the utter academy course page

## **Backend Toko**

NODEJS (April 2021)

Creating API and CRUD using NodeJS framework

## **Project Work SMK TELKOM MALANG**

**PHP** (April 2020)

- Create a bookstore and car rental CRUD website with the PHP programming language.
- In this project I use MYSQL as the database.

## **CERTIFICATE**

## **Microsoft Technology Associate**

Introduction to Programming using JavaScript (December 2021)